{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1) Which one of the following statements is true?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Both Pelton and Francis turbine are impulse turbine",
        "b": "Kaplan turbine is radial flow reaction turbine",
        "c": "Francis turbine is mixed flow reaction turbine",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2) For which of the following minimum values of available heads may Francis turbine be used?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "250 m",
        "b": "150 m",
        "c": "100 m",
        "d": "40 m"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3) Which turbine has maximum number of blades:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Pelton",
        "b": "Francis",
        "c": "Kaplan",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4)In Francis turbine, pressure at inlet is ………. than the pressure at outlet:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "more",
        "b": "same",
        "c": "less",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5) Available head in case of Francis turbine is converted:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "completely into velocity head",
        "b": "completely into pressure head",
        "c": "partially into velocity head and pressure head",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },{
      "question": "6) Cross section of blade of a Francis turbine is ____________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "oval",
        "b": "square ",
        "c": "rectangular",
        "d": "airfoil"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7) A Francis turbine is:  ________ ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "inward flow reaction turbine",
        "b": "inward flow impulse turbine",
        "c": "outward flow reaction turbine",
        "d": "outward flow impulse turbine"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8) ________ is a major problem with Francis turbine",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Efficiency",
        "b": "Installation",
        "c": "Speed regulation",
        "d": "Cavitation"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9)The outlet of the Francis turbine is through _______",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Vane Blades",
        "b": "Draft tube",
        "c": "Directly to atmosphere",
        "d": "Pump"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10)The power output of Francis turbine ranges from__________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "5 kW to 800 MW",
        "b": "1000 kW to 2000 MW",
        "c": "2000 kW to 3000 MW",
        "d": "5000 kW and above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
